<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Standing DevOps</title>
    <link>https://minac.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Standing DevOps</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 19:04:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://minac.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get multiple domains pointing to GitHub Pages using Cloudflare</title>
      <link>https://minac.github.io/2017-05-12-multiple-domains-github-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 19:04:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minac.github.io/2017-05-12-multiple-domains-github-pages/</guid>
      <description>I recently created a one-man-company to do IT Infrastructure consulting (I even got some cute business cards!). The name of the company is Curious Elephant and as part of creating the company in Portugal I get free DNS (curious-elephant.pt) and web hosting for a year. So I ditched the web hosting and wanted to simply point the company URL to this website.
What you can learn from this post  How not to add multiple custom domains to GitHub Pages How setup domain redirection in Cloudflare  The naive approach As you may or may not have noticed this is done using Jekyll and GitHub Pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My MySQL Cookbook</title>
      <link>https://minac.github.io/2017-04-09-mysql-cookbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 12:33:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minac.github.io/2017-04-09-mysql-cookbook/</guid>
      <description>Over the years I&amp;rsquo;ve been accumulating notes on how to do quick operations in a variety of technologies. These have been, up to now, for my eyes only, and they aim to be the documentation I wish I found online on how to quickly get something done in tech X. Today I decided to share some notes of one of those technologies: MySQL.
Disclaimer: These notes are valid at the moment of writing and not for all versions of MySQL (I am testing 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to make Jekyll multilingual</title>
      <link>https://minac.github.io/2017-04-04-how-to-make-jekyll-multilingual/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 15:29:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minac.github.io/2017-04-04-how-to-make-jekyll-multilingual/</guid>
      <description>One of the few requirements that existed for this blog was to be multilingual. This is something that one can easily do with WordPress these days, but then I got turned on to GitHub Pages and one thing led to another and …. many hours later I had a blog that became multilingual, through mercilessly hacking the beautiful Whiteglass theme. Here is a brief explanation of how I made it happen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcasts I listen to</title>
      <link>https://minac.github.io/2017-03-30-podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 13:23:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minac.github.io/2017-03-30-podcasts/</guid>
      <description>I was asked the other day by a friend going on a long trip which podcasts I listen to. I typically listen to them while running, but they&amp;rsquo;re all safe for driving as well. Disclaimer: The list is entirely personal and subjective.
What you can learn from this post  Podcasts which I find interesting and actively listen to in different categories  Entrepeneurial  Side Hustle School From Scratch How I built this Open for business Startup Inc Uncensored  Economics  Freakanomics Radio</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An ansible role for Anchor CMS</title>
      <link>https://minac.github.io/2017-03-30-ansible-anchor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 13:06:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minac.github.io/2017-03-30-ansible-anchor/</guid>
      <description>What you can learn from this post  How to install Anchor CMS How to write an ansible role ready for Ansible Galaxy  What we want to do In broad strokes, this is what we want to do:
 Update your system apt-get update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; apt-get upgrade
 Install the required packages apt-get install unzip vim apache2 libapache2-mod-php5 mysql-server php5-curl php5-mcrypt php5-gd php5-mysql
 Secure your mysql install</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hi, I&#39;m Miguel</title>
      <link>https://minac.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 21:07:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minac.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>{:height=&amp;ldquo;300px&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;200px&amp;rdquo;}
I am a Linux Systems Administrator and Cloud Architect (with a slant to DevOps methods and culture). I am also a slow moving digital nomad, photographer, European-Portuguese and co-founder of a food tour company.
I provide consultancy in the form of training, infrastructure-as-code, cloud migrations and best practice implementations. I&amp;rsquo;ve been told that I&amp;rsquo;m a &amp;ldquo;sociable geek&amp;rdquo; as I aim to be the bridge between the tech and non-tech world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New blog, new life</title>
      <link>https://minac.github.io/2017-03-04-new-blog-new-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 16:12:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minac.github.io/2017-03-04-new-blog-new-life/</guid>
      <description>Welcome! This blog has had several iterations over the years. Most of its life was in a self hosted WordPress, a bit in Anchor, a bit in Ghost and finally in Medium. As the continuous experiment that it is, now it&amp;rsquo;s a mix of Jekyll and Github Pages fronted by the amazing Cloudflare. It&amp;rsquo;s fun and easy to blog again and I don&amp;rsquo;t have to pay anyone to host me, so expect a bunch of small posts coming up!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to deny hot linking from your AWS S3 files</title>
      <link>https://minac.github.io/2015-05-25-how-to-deny-hot-linking-from-your-aws-s3-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2014 13:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minac.github.io/2015-05-25-how-to-deny-hot-linking-from-your-aws-s3-files/</guid>
      <description>There are many good people in the web, but there are also those who are lazy and instead of creating content themselves or even hosting it, they will want to abuse the existing stuff online. For example, say you have a bucket (originally) called mybucket and a file called … myfile.jpg. You uploaded the file to AWS S3 and now you are serving it from there through a webpage that we’ll call test.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S3/Cloudfront Access Denied</title>
      <link>https://minac.github.io/2015-05-20-s3-cloudfront-access-denied/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 13:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minac.github.io/2015-05-20-s3-cloudfront-access-denied/</guid>
      <description>So you finally listened the SEO guys who keep saying that the images on your website have to be fast and you decided to move them from your small cloud server to an AWS S3 bucket? You managed to create the bucket and even enabled Cloudfront on that bucket so that the images (or other files) are not only in one region of AWS but everywhere in the world (well, every edge node on AWSs Content Delivery Network).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Today I had some fun with cows saying fortunes</title>
      <link>https://minac.github.io/2015-05-18-today-i-had-some-fun-with-cows-saying-fortunes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2014 13:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://minac.github.io/2015-05-18-today-i-had-some-fun-with-cows-saying-fortunes/</guid>
      <description>Today I had some fun with cows saying fortunes. If you are not in the Linux world, it will seem like I’ve been smoking some strange Dalmatian herbs, but if you have played at all with Linux you’ll know this happy face:
_________________________________________ / You will be reincarnated as a toad; and \ \ you will be much happier. / ----------------------------------------- \ (__) (oo) /------\/ / | || * /\---/\ ~~ ~~  Now, who said geeks don’t know how to have fun?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>